<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web on Wesley Hales</title>
    <link>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/tags/web/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web on Wesley Hales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wesleyhales.com:1313/tags/web/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Mobile With RichFaces! Design Proposals - Day2</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/blog/2011/08/02/going-mobile-with-richfaces-design-proposals---day2</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/blog/2011/08/02/going-mobile-with-richfaces-design-proposals---day2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 2 of the RichFaces skinning and we have the first approach for tablet devices. Tablets are a little harder to design for because of a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;1) Your design sits on the fine line between desktop and mobile. You are designing your app for a max 1024 pixel resolution (in landscape mode) but you must also take advantage of mobile usability (which you will see in page2)&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;2) Similar to the iPad Mail.app, it&amp;#8216;s almost like you are designing 2 different UI&amp;#8216;s for landscape and portrait modes. For portrait you need more drop down menus, and for landscape you can try to fit everything on one page without the drop downs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/rf.tablet.day2.page1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;RichFace Mobile Skin1&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; width=&#34;225px&#34; src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/rf.tablet.day2.page1-small.JPG&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p class=&#34;pTitle&#34;&gt;Day 2: About The Design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
Here we have the interaction broken out into 2 pages. The first page shows the primary menu and isn&amp;#8216;t all that exciting.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Notice how, unlike the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wesleyhales.com/entry/going_mobile_with_richfaces_we&#34;&gt;iphone design from Day 1&lt;/a&gt;, I left the browser button overrides within the app itself. Tablet web apps are completely use case driven so this will vary. But since we have so much more real estate, we can play around with standard navigation options that keep the user&#39;s attention focused on the app itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/rf.tablet.day2.page2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin:0 7px 0 0;&#34; alt=&#34;RichFace Mobile Skin1&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; width=&#34;225px&#34; src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/rf.tablet.day2.page2-small.JPG&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
The second page is what you see after selecting a menu item from page 1 (click to enlarge). Here we have the title bar at the top left with a built in back button which takes the user back to the first screen.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;To the right of the title you see the secondary menu represented by rounded rectangles. Next is the main content of the page broken out into content and actionable panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally you have the big arrows to the right and left. These arrows are &amp;#8220;thumb reachable&amp;#8221; which is a common usability pattern in portrait mode tablets. It provides an easy page flip access to all of the RichFaces components within the top level category.&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The great thing about CSS3 transitions is that you can really make a UI like this scream and flow seamlessly. So you can imagine how tapping an arrow with your thumb will slide in a new component demo and gracefully highlight the secondary menu option at the top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;So this concludes our design for Day 2. As I said earlier, this is more of a use case driven design. WE could spawn a very minimalistic skin and component look and feel from this. However, It would be more to display the power behind RichFaces ajax and templating features as the user moves through the app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Mobile With RichFaces! Design Proposals - Day1</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/blog/2011/08/01/going-mobile-with-richfaces-design-proposals---day1</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/blog/2011/08/01/going-mobile-with-richfaces-design-proposals---day1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today marks an important day in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jboss.org/richfaces&#34;&gt;RichFaces project&lt;/a&gt; as we continue to head down the mobile web road. Since we have such a great community of users and followers, we want you to be involved with the design process.&lt;br /&gt; 
So each day this week, I will come up with a new proposed design/theme for RichFaces Mobile and we want to hear your feedback. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will announce each new design (both for tablet and phone) via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/richfaces&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; with a link back to this article. I will try my best to pick apart each design and describe why I did what I did, and hope you can give me some real world feedback. We want this project to actually make sense and be usable to what you guys are facing in the real world. Without further adieu....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/rf-mobile-skin1.JPG&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;RichFace Mobile Skin1&#34; align=&#34;right&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34; src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/rf-mobile-skin1-small.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Our first task is to tackle the RichFaces showcase of components. Classifying what is mobile ready and which components may need a little work.&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;p class=&#34;pTitle&#34;&gt;Day 1: About The Design&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
Here we have what could be the RichFaces component showcase skin. This is what I will be posting a new version of each day this week.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;In this design we have the standard browser “functionality take over” at the top header. The custom back button is essential to mobile web design and must be overridden here &amp;#8211; following the pattern of previous designs.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Nothing too different about the standard menu options and detail options (center stage). Following convention here as well. One thing I am adhering too are the usability guidelines set forth by Jakob Nielsen&amp;#8216;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nngroup.com/reports/mobile/ipad/&#34;&gt;Usability of iPad Apps and Websites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;To get the full tab bar at the bottom (and to replicate the native feel) the user must bookmark the application. I think it makes sense for this menu to be contextual to the app and provide other alternate routes.&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>