<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on Wesley Hales</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on Wesley Hales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AeroGear - Mobile, HTML5, and Auwesome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/02/08/AeroGear-Mobile-HTML5-and-Auwesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/02/08/AeroGear-Mobile-HTML5-and-Auwesome/</guid>
      <description>The AeroGear project had it&#39;s official launch last week and I want to review what we&#39;re doing and where we&#39;re headed. For starters, AeroGear is focused on:  Education - Screencasts, Tutorials, and Quickstarts for running any (HTML5, Hybrid, Native) mobile solution with JBoss projects and app servers. Innovation - Many of AeroGear&#39;s primary goals are to provide HTML5 extensions for web applications, both mobile and desktop based. Community - We already have several community members contributing examples, demos, and other useful resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RichFaces Mobile Designs - Day 3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/03/RichFaces-Mobile-Designs-Day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/03/RichFaces-Mobile-Designs-Day-3/</guid>
      <description>So I made it over the hump of this mobile design week of madness. Below you will find a dark theme with a component skin for the rich:accordion component.

Day 3: About The Design
Here we have another phone based design broke out into 3 pages.
The first page is a standard menu so not much to say there. The bottom menu bar is a little different from my first design &amp;#8211; following the lead of the native twitter iPhone app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Mobile With RichFaces! Design Proposals - Day2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/02/Going-Mobile-With-RichFaces-Design-Proposals-Day2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/02/Going-Mobile-With-RichFaces-Design-Proposals-Day2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 of the RichFaces skinning and we have the first approach for tablet devices. Tablets are a little harder to design for because of a few reasons:
1) Your design sits on the fine line between desktop and mobile. You are designing your app for a max 1024 pixel resolution (in landscape mode) but you must also take advantage of mobile usability (which you will see in page2)
2) Similar to the iPad Mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Mobile With RichFaces! Design Proposals - Day1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/01/Going-Mobile-With-RichFaces-Design-Proposals-Day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/01/Going-Mobile-With-RichFaces-Design-Proposals-Day1/</guid>
      <description>Today marks an important day in the RichFaces project as we continue to head down the mobile web road. Since we have such a great community of users and followers, we want you to be involved with the design process.
So each day this week, I will come up with a new proposed design/theme for RichFaces Mobile and we want to hear your feedback. I will announce each new design (both for tablet and phone) via twitter with a link back to this article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>