<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Wesley Hales</title>
    <link>http://wesleyhales.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Wesley Hales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wesleyhales.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>From Startup to Enterprise</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2013/12/17/from-startup-to-enterprise</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2013/12/17/from-startup-to-enterprise</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2013 I was given the incredible opportunity to start with an empty canvas and come up with a completely new web application for Apigee.
For the past year I&amp;rsquo;ve been heads down on merging Apigee&amp;rsquo;s Usergrid and Mobile Analytics products using AngularJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those interested: Usergrid, a
Backend as a Service, was acquired by Apigee in early 2012 and has served as the core tool of all Apigee trainings and developer outreach efforts.
Developers use it to create a backend for their mobile apps amongst many other things like managing users, roles and permissions.
The Mobile Analytics product is something I was partial to since I created the original UI - before it was acquired by Apigee. I wanted to carry it past
the acquisition and endure the process of turning it into a full fledged enterprise offering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a retrospective - carrying an idea from startup to enterprise product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;let-s-start-with-the-design&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started brainstorming for the new UI on February 1st. Originally we set out to only deliver a new analytics dashboard, but were soon asked to merge
the existing UserGrid project into the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the first designs and wireframes we came up with. I purposely left everything greyscale to allow for a pure focus on the page data and layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/first-design-a-large.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/first-design-a.png&#34; class=&#34;margin10 max-width-100 float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/first-design-b-large.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/first-design-b.png&#34; class=&#34;margin10 max-width-100 float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/first-design-c-large.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/first-design-c.png&#34; class=&#34;margin10 max-width-100 float-left&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br class=&#34;clear-left&#34;/&gt;
The layouts above took around 1 month to deliver, and many of the UI elements were reworked from the old UI. Most of the work went into the new look and feel and
reformatting the data to appear more readable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the team was in agreement on how the pages should be structured, we then went into the finer design details. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of weird (and welcomed) being the designer
AND developer for a given project. I mean, that&amp;rsquo;s what startups are all about - doing everything and playing all the roles - but when you get into larger
companies and work with larger teams, people start to look at you a little funny and the criticism is a little heavier. And that&amp;rsquo;s totally expected and
understandable, because as companies grow it only makes sense to hire these things out to design firms that are doing this stuff day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So navigation design is always a fun topic amongst developers and designers. Especially when some products use a horizontal design and others choose vertical.
It really depends on the usecase on which way you should go. We went with the vertical menu in this case because the end user (developers) would be
building an app with our UI. It only made sense to see and understand each tool we were providing on a visual level, and not hidden away in a horizontal menu with
drop downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the evolution of our menu design in chronological order from left to right. Design is an iterative process for me and
I never get it right on the first go. And it really helps to have good feedback from other &amp;ldquo;design minded&amp;rdquo; folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/menus-large.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/menus-large.png&#34; class=&#34;margin10 max-width-100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to leave a lot of the original grey design from the mockups and not get too heavy handed with the colors. After all, we were
building an analytics dashboard that needed to put heavy emphasis on errors, warnings, and other alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/app-erros.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/app-erros.png&#34; class=&#34;margin10 max-width-100&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The style guide is still in the works. Luckily Apigee already had one, so I leveraged all the existing colors and fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-code&#34;&gt;The Code&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By mid-April, we had most of the feedback implemented into the wireframes and were ready to move forward with development. During
this month and in between feedback rounds, I was evaluating both Ember and AngularJS. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to turn this into
a discussion of which framework I think is better - they both have their strengths and weaknesses - but I will tell you why I
went with Angular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community - When I opt for a framework, it has to be strongly backed by the community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Components - I like the web components approach that Angular has going with directives. And putting heavy emphasis on this from the start was a good move by the
Angular team. Directives, love or hate, are a huge win for gaining community support and contributions. I&amp;rsquo;ve also recently seen a few conference speakers focus their entire
session on directives. Sure, there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a learning curve, but the concept is well received by most front-end devs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Productivity - I liked being productive. This post is a testament to being productive, seeing that two developers could stand up an entire analytics and BaaS dashboard within 6 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecture - Angular sets forth the idea of a loosely coupled architecture for building large apps. The mechanisms for dependency injection and scope management were attractive to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On May 1st I had the markup and a beginning on the Angular architecture all pushed to github. From May into the late summer months we were
busting ass trying to get this dashboard completed. I was mainly working on the global parts of the app along with the monitoring dashboard, and we had
one other developer focusing on rewriting the existing Usergrid Backbone application into Angular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/github.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/posts/2013-12-17/github.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 500px&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On August 9th we had our first C-Level review of the beta version of the product. This is pretty significant seeing that two developers were
able to produce a massive SPA in a little over 3 months. Not to mention managing vacation schedules and other things that arose. Of course,
We still had a ways to go in polishing the application and not to mention testing, but overall we were able to get a lot done in a short
amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of projects and articles that resulted from this work:
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wesleyhales/angular-charts&#34;&gt;Angular Charts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2013/10/23/Basic-Screen-Updates-with-Angular-and-requestAnimationFrame/&#34;&gt;Basic Screen Updates with Angular and requestAnimationFrame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons I like Angular for 2013, 2014, and maybe even 2015. But another framework will come in &amp;lt;= 3 years time, and it will be even more productive and we&amp;rsquo;ll
 be rewriting a new product all over again. That&amp;rsquo;s the nature of the beast and it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to many other 3 year life cycles we see in the tech industry. Bottom line: Don&amp;rsquo;t religiously buy into
 any web framework. Use it at face value and always be prepared for the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way, I had brilliant input and help from many awesome folks. The product manager for this effort was &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/karlunho&#34;&gt;Alan Ho&lt;/a&gt;, and I would not
have been able to forge a usable product without his vision of how things should come together. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/edanuff&#34;&gt;Ed Anuff&lt;/a&gt;, the founder of Usergrid, was truly a pleasure
to work with/for and receive guidance from during many frustrating times. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/prabhatjha&#34;&gt;Prabhat Jha&lt;/a&gt;, my long time pal worked tirelessly to setup the RESTful
endpoints I needed to get the job done (along with countless other backend pieces). And last but not least, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rockerston&#34;&gt;Rod Simpson&lt;/a&gt; who stepped in to help with the
Backbone-to-Angular rewrite of the existing UserGrid product. Rod also has an impressive design background and helped/pushed me to design a better product
when I hit blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can try the dashboard out for yourself &lt;a href=&#34;https://apigee.com/usergrid&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Lemme know what you think!
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Firefox 3 theme</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2008/08/26/creating-a-firefox-3-theme</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2008/08/26/creating-a-firefox-3-theme</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:5px; margin:5px; background-color:#f9f5ae; border:1px solid #b2ac4f;&#34;&gt;**UPDATE - This theme is now available on Mozilla.org here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/9627/&#34; style=&#34;color:#20aa30&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/9627/&#34;&gt;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/9627/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/jroller/ff3-theme-large.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/jroller/ff3-themeclose.gif&#34; style=&#34;margin:5px;&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to tryout Firefox theme building a few weeks ago on vacation. It took me a few days to design the skin and slice up all the images for theme creation. But once it came to laying down the Firefox CSS, I have to say that I was a little overwhelmed and haven&amp;rsquo;t been back to finish the theme since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course this could be due to me actually having a day job and somewhat of a life. I think the overall css code for the layout is fairly simple. All you have to do is get your x,y coordinates right and you are golden. If anybody has any quick tips to make the process of placing the buttons a little simpler, please speak now! Or if someone wants to take on the task of completing this theme I will post the .psd files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/jroller/ff3-theme-large.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com/images/jroller/ff3-theme-small.gif&#34; style=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the cooler things about this theme is that the icons are 100% original. We all know most themes take some form of Windows or *nix icons. I tried to take the old 1930&amp;rsquo;s cinema approach where I could. But I couldn&amp;rsquo;t come up with anything for the copy and paste buttons (C and V).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another design</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2007/10/29/another-design</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2007/10/29/another-design</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The designer inside me just won&#39;t give up. I have tried and tried to put down the Photoshop paint brush and embrace development only, but it just isn&#39;t going to happen. I care just as much about semantic HTML and css/designer stuff as I do about hard core Java development. &lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Some say it&#39;s easy to be a jack of all trades and a master of none. But I am naturally forced to slap that theory in the face and then kick it in the balls ;-)&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;With that said, enjoy the new layout and be ready for another in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another design</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2007/10/29/another-design</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2007/10/29/another-design</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The designer inside me just won&#39;t give up. I have tried and tried to put down the Photoshop paint brush and embrace development only, but it just isn&#39;t going to happen. I care just as much about semantic HTML and css/designer stuff as I do about hard core Java development. &lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Some say it&#39;s easy to be a jack of all trades and a master of none. But I am naturally forced to slap that theory in the face and then kick it in the balls ;-)&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;With that said, enjoy the new layout and be ready for another in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another blog layout</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2007/03/11/another-blog-layout</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2007/03/11/another-blog-layout</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So my current design is serving the purpose, but it seems a little &amp;ldquo;bland&amp;rdquo;. I finally nailed down a design that is a little more frameworked. What I mean is, most of the time websites are designed to serve the content at hand. Which is fine in most cases, but I am looking for something more than just a &amp;ldquo;nice look&amp;rdquo; out of my designs. For some reason I can&amp;rsquo;t get away from grey and other neutral colors. Maybe cause it&amp;rsquo;s just the trend right now, but it seems to work and no matter what other colors I try in my designs, I always come back to grey. Also, the graphite pattern on the banner is kind of in style now (although it has been for the past 6 months), but by the time I code the css for this and integrate it into jroller - it will be time to do another design ?!?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;width:100%; text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;src=&#34;/images/jroller/new-layout2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;src=&#34;/images/jroller/new-layout2_small.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Jroller Blog Extreme Makeover</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2006/12/18/my-jroller-blog-extreme-makeover</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com/blog/2006/12/18/my-jroller-blog-extreme-makeover</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I need a new design badly (the little British car in the tunnel is getting old, quick), and after coding for x number of months, I feel like my design skillz are getting a little stale. So here are the candidates for my new look.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p class=&#34;pTitle&#34;&gt;Layout #1&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;src=&#34;/images/jroller/blogLayout_2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;src=&#34;/images/jroller/blogLayout_2_small.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p class=&#34;pTitle&#34;&gt;Layout #2&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;src=&#34;/images/jroller/blogLayout.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;src=&#34;/images/jroller/blogLayout_small.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;357&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>