<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hard on Wesley Hales</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/hard/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hard on Wesley Hales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/hard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My 4 month old MacBook Pro Hardrive is skippping... badly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2008/03/31/my-4-month-old-macbook-pro-hardrive-is-skippping...-badly</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2008/03/31/my-4-month-old-macbook-pro-hardrive-is-skippping...-badly</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s never a good thing when your hard drive starts making that funny little skipping noise. But, it&#39;s really not good when you push the power button and all you hear are loud ass clicks and you can feel the vibration of each click on the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In all my wise &#39;ol years in the IT industry, I have never had this happen to me. Sure, I&#39;ve had old hd&#39;s that eventually wear out and start skipping. But not on a brand new shiny 17&#34; MBP that is only a few months old! And then of course the first thing anyone asks you is if you have backups or use Time Machine - and what do you think my answer is :) I know, I know, blah blah Time Machine is so easy or why couldn&#39;t I have just copied my work files to my usb thumbdrive.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;After reality sets in with these types of situations, you start thinking outside of your little world of sitting behind a desk and writing code all day. I don&#39;t know, I just felt like doing something crazy. Kind of like our good friends from OfficeSpace...&lt;object width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/T6syezOHJ2Q&amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;wmode&#34; value=&#34;transparent&#34;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/T6syezOHJ2Q&amp;hl=en&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; wmode=&#34;transparent&#34; width=&#34;425&#34; height=&#34;355&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;And after the anger you immediately start freaking out and backup things that still remain on your other systems. I have never been so diligent about my backup scripts in all my life.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;I think (for us) maintaining any MP3 and picture collection over the past 10 years has been quite a challenge. If you have been fortunate/smart enough to maintain all of those songs and images (especially from the napster/mp3 galaxy days) then I applaud thee. And if you haven&#39;t backed your shiz up lately... then don&#39;t be like me and think that your computer is too new and you can put it off for a few more days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>