<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Html5 on Wesley Hales</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/html5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Html5 on Wesley Hales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/html5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 is Booming in Atlanta</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/07/19/HTML5-is-Booming-in-Atlanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/07/19/HTML5-is-Booming-in-Atlanta/</guid>
      <description>So, all I can say is that the Atlanta HTML5 community is awesome. Today the @atlhtml5 user group has reached it&amp;rsquo;s 1000th member! From startups to companies in the Alexa top 20 rankings, Atlanta is heading towards a bright future in innovation and the open web. Front-end developers are in serious demand as Atlanta based companies strive to build web applications that are more offline accessible, responsive, and performant. Companies are moving more JavaScript to the browser, and this demands more structured code following MVC style patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing Content with Web Intents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/07/11/Sharing-Content-with-Web-Intents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/07/11/Sharing-Content-with-Web-Intents/</guid>
      <description>The Intent of Sharing If you employ share buttons on your site, then you might already be aware of the increased load that comes with trying to make your content social. Allowing users to take action on your specific content and &amp;ldquo;share&amp;rdquo; it is a common task. Much like linking HTML documents together, we are now linking apps together that are capable of pushing content to a receiving service via the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushing CDI Events to the Browser with WebSockets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/01/20/Pushing-CDI-Events-to-the-Browser-with-WebSockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2012/01/20/Pushing-CDI-Events-to-the-Browser-with-WebSockets/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer: Minimal load testing was performed with 10000 concurrent WebSocket connections. You can see some true performance numbers here.      
Here is the demo in action. As you can see on the right, I have 2 chat windows open and on the left we have a member registration. Users are chatting across a raw WebSocket connection and when another user registers, the CDI event is fired all the way through to the browser as a JavaScript alert via the connected WebSocket clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Ajax on Mobile Devices (with HTML5)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/29/Fixing-Ajax-on-Mobile-Devices-with-HTML5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/08/29/Fixing-Ajax-on-Mobile-Devices-with-HTML5/</guid>
      <description>Update: @_boye has created a perf test which shows the performance of this solution. Remarkably, This iFrame solution outperforms innerHTML on Firefox 7 and maintains the same speed on Chrome 16.
The most common approach for receiving markup from an Ajax request is to use innerHTML for placement of the responseText. This method has been widely used (and argued) since the inception of XHR, but it surprises me that it&#39;s still being recommended and used not only on desktop browsers but mobile ones as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replacing Photoshop With CSS3 - Creating Styles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/02/05/Replacing-Photoshop-With-CSS3-Creating-Styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/02/05/Replacing-Photoshop-With-CSS3-Creating-Styles/</guid>
      <description>One trendy technique that I often use in Photoshop (for buttons, nav bars, etc&amp;#8230;) is a gradient that slightly variates from its base color with a hint of inner shadow (for highlight).
This used to be a pain in the royal ass to implement with html/css2, but now is amazingly simple with CSS3. Not only is it simple, but you can also create a sort of &amp;#8220;gradient template&amp;#8220; to be reused.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>