<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opensocial on Wesley Hales</title>
    <link>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/tags/opensocial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opensocial on Wesley Hales</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://wesleyhales.com:1313/tags/opensocial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an OpenSocial Portlet</title>
      <link>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/blog/2008/10/12/developing-an-opensocial-portlet</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://wesleyhales.com:1313/blog/2008/10/12/developing-an-opensocial-portlet</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/Picture-6.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://wesleyhales.com:1313/images/jroller/Picture-6-small.jpg&#34; style=&#34;margin:5px;&#34; align=&#34;right&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I dedicated some time this weekend to creating a fully functional demo with OpenSocial, Shindig and JBoss Portal. It seems like OpenSocial has a lot of new supported platforms coming out in 0.8 and the future is looking promising. Here is a bullet list to summarize what I found:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation is scarce when you want to roll you own OS container via Shindig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luckily &lt;a href=&#34;http://chrisschalk.com/shindig_docs/io/shindig-io.html&#34;&gt;Chris Schalk&lt;/a&gt; did a good job providing some documentation on getting persistence setup on a mysql db&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unfortunately, due to the bleeding edge of this technology, some of (the few) demos that exist don&amp;rsquo;t work with today&amp;rsquo;s Shindig trunk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was able to quickly learn Google widgeting and am on my way to being a &amp;ldquo;widget master&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next on the list is to mess around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://code.google.com/apis/opensocial/articles/authsub.html&#34;&gt;Google Data APIs in OpenSocial Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transition/integration of Shindig into a standard webapp/portlet was a huge pita. Too many hard coded servlet context in .js files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It seems like (for now) you really need to be into the Orkut scene to leverage current social users. Myspace is something I try to stay away from, and I was really hoping to see some LinkedIn stuff but was let down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is definitely the way portals are headed and I guess I will try to muster up the energy to write an article once the kinks are worked out of my demo. I would also like to do something cool with the collected social data inside of a portal environment (like notifications of other user activities, posts, changes, etc&amp;hellip;). I used the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoq.com/articles/jsf-ajax-seam-portlets-pt-2&#34;&gt;JBoss Portlet Bridge Richfaces&lt;/a&gt; project/archetype to create the demo. The bridge makes it incredibly easy to do stuff like this because of having things working on both the servlet and portlet side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>